[Music]
[Applause]
i am here with my client raya here in
glute lab las vegas
and today's video is going to be on the
bc pyramid now i first
thought up the bc pyramid in glute lab
san diego and this was in july of 2018
and it was so effective it's a four-week
protocol it was so effective
that yeah i made a graphic i made a big
deal out of it and
since then people have saw great results
but i have never introduced this on
youtube so
uh i thought it would be worthwhile to
go through the protocol and
show raya actually performing it it's
four sets you can adjust the load
based on your fitness level like if
you're a beginner
you might have to go markedly lighter
and if you're very advanced you might go
heavier but
i'm going to use the same loads i
started off my glute lab san diego
clients with which was 225 for set one
and i had him do 15 reps then 275 for
set
two and they would do 10 reps then 325
for set three and they would do five
reps then i would strip the weight
off put a glute loop around their knees
and have them do
20 reps with 185 that was their starting
point they were all around the same
strength
then that was their baseline they'd use
the same weight
all four weeks with the goal of
increasing reps
now you're gonna rest around three
minutes in between sets
except for the last set you don't rest
as long maybe one to two minutes
the tempo is one second up one second
down no pauses and obviously you want to
use a full range of motion and good form
no junk reps throughout the month so
let's get right to it
so this is set one we have 225 on the
bar
rya's gonna go for 15 reps go for it
one two touchdown
three four
five six
seven eight
nine 10
11 12
13 14
15. good okay now
we set the timer for three minutes now
during the three minute stress i'm gonna
stop a 25 pound plate on each side
bringing the weight up to 275 for set
number two
okay so the three minutes is up again
275 on the bar
we are going for 10 reps ready go
one two
three four
five six
seven eight
nine one more ten good
all right we're going to rest three
minutes again and i'm gonna put another
25 pound plate on the bar
which will bring it to 325. we just
rested three minutes the weight is 3.25
ryan's going for five solid reps
three two more four last one
five good okay now we're only resting
two minutes
i'm going to take weight off the bar i'm
going to go down to 185
i'm going to put this glute loop around
her knees and we'll go for 20 reps
okay we just rested two minutes not
three so this is less rest time
we dropped the weight down to 185 so
less weight and i threw a glute loop
around
raya's knees okay we're going to do 20
constant tension reps
go for it first step
from here raya doesn't start lifting
from here the first step
she's going to abduct as far as she can
there hold it there the whole time and
do the 20 reps
one two fast three
faster four five
six this is constant tension style seven
eight
nine ten eleven
twelve thirteen push the knees out more
fourteen
fifteen sixteen seventeen
eighteen two more nineteen
good okay so now you get the idea uh
that's the bc pyramid but that's only
week one
here's what you need to know it's a four
week protocol
she just got 50 total reps so i'm gonna
give you a pdf that goes along with this
so in the description
you can click on the link and download
the pdf and you can fill this out
so week one she got 15 10
5 and 20. that totals up to 50 reps
your goal is to get around 60 reps on
the same protocol for week two
then week three you want to get around
65 reps then week four
70 reps it's going to be tough you're
going to be pushing yourself hard
but that's what causes the glutes to
grow that's what causes adaptation so
that's the bc pyramid
thank you raya for demoing if you like
this video
please hit like be sure to leave a
comment if you try it out let me know
what you think and obviously make sure
you subscribe to the channel
thanks for watching so in this video
raya used
225 275 325
and 185 pounds for her four sets but you
need to adjust these loads according to
your fitness levels
you might use 95 115
135 and 65 for your sets if you're a
beginner
you know or if you're exceptionally
strong maybe use 315
365 and 415
and then drop down to like 225
that would be an example for a very
strong person adjust
according to your strength levels but
you set a baseline
it's going to total around 50 reps and
then you just try to increase reps
throughout the month now this is a
four-week protocol you don't keep doing
it back to back
for eight weeks or 12 weeks you just do
the four weeks extending the protocol
longer than that would probably lead to
spinning your wheels and overreaching
now you can do it a couple times a year
i wouldn't do it more than twice though
so like for example you could do it in
like
march and then do it again in you know
like september or something
just make sure there's at least a few
months in between your pyramid months
make sure you print
and fill out the pdf so you can track
and total your reps and when the four
weeks are up
you should have stronger and bigger
glutes i know my clients did when they
first tried this
now if this video intrigued you and you
would like to train
under my system using my principles then
i invite you to click on the link below
and subscribe to booty by brett and join
the thousands of other happy members
who are seeing amazing results